Guide to the Palestinian Student Films, 2012-2020 RL.11839
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Palestinian Student films
2012-2020
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kalow, Nancy
RL.11839
61 items
37 Gigabytes
Forty-three films by 44 Palestinian student filmmakers, created between 2012 and 2020, documenting or portraying the political context and lived experience in the West Bank and Gaza.
Arrangement
Films arranged alphabetically by first listed filmmaker.
Biographical / Historical
In 2017, 2018, and 2019, student filmmakers from Birzeit University, Al-Quds University, Al-Quds Bard University, Dar Al-Kalima University (Bethlehem), Hebron University, Palestine Polytechnic University (Hebron), An-Najah University (Nablus), Al-Azhar University (Gaza) and Al-Aqsa University (Gaza) submitted short student productions for inclusion in an annual film festival at Duke University, coordinated by Nancy Kalow, Lecturing Fellow at the Center for Documentary Studies. The festival continued in 2020, with themes including the COVID-19 pandemic.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Palestine Student Films were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2020.
Collection Overview
43 films by 44 Palestinian student filmmakers, created between 2012 and 2020, documenting or portraying the political context and lived experience in the West Bank and Gaza. The films were made in journalism, media, and film classes at nine Palestinian universities, and range from experimental and poetic, to documentary essay and ethnography, to scripted narrative fiction. The films are characterized by their high technical quality, their local feel and community-centered focus, and their varied expression of Palestinian identity. The filmmakers include Amjad Abu Baker, Noor AbuGhaniah, Mohammed Abd El Aziz Abu Hamam, Salah AbuNe'ma, Rayhan Abu Omar, Baha' Abu Shanab, Sarah AbuShusheh, Raja Ahmad, Alaa Alaloul, Mai Alami, Mohammad Alazza, Thaer Al Azzah, Lillian Al Azzeh, Ahmad Al-Bazz, Amjad M. A. Al Fayoumi, Sanabel Al-Hoot, Mohamed Nayef Ahmed Ali, Wisam Al-Jafari, Fatma Adel Qasem Alqadi, Maysa Al-Shaer, Anas Ashreef, Mahmoud Awad, Shayma' Awadeh, Alaa Dayeh, Omar Elemawi, Mohammed S. Ewais, Mohammad Houshieh, Yaser Jodallah, Abeer Kaabnah, Lara Khammash, Mohammed Khatib, Shatha Khatib, Aya Ahmed Matrabie, Renad Nasser, Ali Hamdan Okeh, Randa Owdeh, Lana Sadaqa, Yousef Salhi, Mohammed Shalodi, Naser Shatat, Khaled Tuaima, Salam Yahya, and Tala Zeitawi. Formats include MOV, MP4, and MPEG2 video files. Formats include MOV, MP4, and MPEG2 video files, and PNG, JPG, and PDF image files.
Human Rights -- Gaza Strip; Human Rights -- Palestine; Palestine -- Social conditions; Audiovisual materials; Video recordings; Documentary films; Short films; Palestine -- Education; Palestine -- Employment; Palestine -- Sports; Palestine -- Economic conditions; Refugee camps -- Palestine; Jerusalem; West Bank; Gaza; Arab-Israeli conflict; Bethlehem; Rām Allāh; Hebron; COVID-19 Pandemic, 2020-; Kalow, Nancy
- Films shown at the 2017-2019 Duke University Festival of Student Films From Palestine, 2012-2019; 35 items
  Arrangement
  Arrangement is alphabetical by filmmaker.
  Scope and Contents
  Single line descriptions and genre designations provided by the Duke Festival of Palestinian Student Films.
  - Amjad Abu Baker [credited as Amjad Jamal] and Lillian Al Azzeh
    - Endless Dream (حلم موبد), 2018; 00:07:35, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0001, Video-file ENDLESS DREAM FILM.mp4)
      Fiction. Magical visions in a bleak prison (رُؤًى سحرية في سجن مظلم); Keywords: incarceration, dreams (أحلام، سَجن / احتجاز); Associated university/location: Al-Quds University Institute of Modern Media (جامعة القدس معهد الإعلام العصري‎), Ramallah.
  - Mohammed Abd El Aziz Abu Hamam (محمد عبد العزيز ابو حمام )
    - The Gate (البوابة), 2016; 00:03:43, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0002, Video-file the gate البوابة (1080p).mp4)
      Fiction. No way to get through (لا سبيل للعبور); Keywords: Gaza, checkpoints, political commentary (غزة، تعليق سياسي, نقاط التفتيش); Associated university/location: Birzeit University's program in Gaza (جامعة بيرزيت), Gaza.
  - Rayhan Abu Omar, alternate spelling Rihana Abu Omar (ريحان ابو عمر)
    - The Invisible Child (طفل على الهامش), 2015; 00:08:13, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0003, Video-file The Invisible Child.mpg)
      Documentary. A childhood in Hebron (طفولة في الخليل); Keywords: childhood, political commentary, disability (طفولة، إعاقة / عجز، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Hebron University (جامعة الخليل), Hebron.
  - Baha' Abu Shanab (بهاء أبو شنب)
    - The Living of the Pigeons (قوت الحمام), 2014; 00:16:32, 720x480 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0004, Video-file LivingOfThePigeons.mov)
      Documentary. A poetic observation of day laborers going through a checkpoint (رَصْد شعري لعمال مياومة يعبرون حاجزاً عسكرياً); Keywords: checkpoints, employment, political commentary (عمل، تعليق سياسي, نقاط التفتيش); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
      Conditions Governing Access
      This item is only available in the reading room.
  - Noor AbuGhaniah
    - Visitation (زيارة), 2017; 00:12:04, 1280x720 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0005, Video-file Visitation.mp4)
      Documentary. A day-long journey for a brief visit separated by glass (سَفرَة تستغرق يوماً كاملاً من أجل زيارة قصيرة الزجاج فاصلها); Keywords: incarceration, women's roles, family (أسرة، أدوار النساء، سَجن / احتجاز); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Salah AbuNe'ma (صلاح الدين حسين علي ابو نعمة)
    - Burq'o Classic (برقو كلاسيق), 2014; 00:12:46, 1280x720 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0006, Video-file burq'o classic.mp4)
      Fiction. What's in the suitcase? The story of a rebellious young woman (ماذا يوجد في الحقيبة؟ قصة شابة متمردة); Keywords: family, women's roles (أسرة، أدوار النساء); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Sarah AbuShusheh
    - Unfinished, 2019; 00:10:00, 1440x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0007, Video-file Unfinished Sarah Abushusheh copied.mp4)
      Fiction. Re-enacting an interrogation (استجواب الممثلين.); Keywords: checkpoints, women's roles, political commentary (أدوار النساء، تعليق سياسي, نقاط التفتيش); Associated university/location: Al-Quds Bard College
  - Raja Ahmad and Mohammed Khatib
    - In Half (النصف), 2017; 00:12:26, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0008, Video-file In Half.mp4)
      Fiction. Gotta have that jersey (يجب أن أحصل على قميص لاعبي كرة القدم ذلك); Keywords: childhood, family life (أسرة, طفولة); Associated university/location: Al-Quds Ramallah (جامعة القدس), Ramallah.
  - Alaa Alaloul
    - Moving Dream (الحلم المتحرك), 2012; 00:02:00, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0009, Video-file Moving Dream.mp4)
      Fiction. Nader dreams of going back to work (نادر يحلم بالعودة إلى العمل); Keywords: Gaza, employment, dreams, disability (غزة، عمل، أحلام، إعاقة / عجز); Associated university/location: Birzeit University's program in Gaza (جامعة بيرزيت), Gaza.
  - Mohammad Alazza (محمد العزة)
    - We Have a Dream to Live Safe (لدينا حلم العيش بأمان), 2016; 00:12:19, 1280x720 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0010, Video-file We Have a Dream to Live Safe.mp4)
      Documentary. Aida refugee camp through the eyes of Shahd Awais (مخيم عايدة للاجئين في عيون شهد عويس); Keywords: refugee camp life, childhood, political commentary (حياة مخيم اللاجئين، طفولة، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
    - What Will You Do When You Go Back To Your Village (ماذا ستفعل عندما تعود لقريتك؟ ), 2016; 00:03:39, 1280x720 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0011, Video-file What will you do when you go back to your Village.mp4)
      Documentary. Ideas for the future and memories of the past (أفكار للمستقبل وذكريات الماضي); Keywords: 1948, refugee camp life, political commentary, dreams (حياة مخيم اللاجئين، أحلام، تعليق سياسي, 1948); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Mohamed Nayef Ahmed Ali
    - My 3 Dreams (الحلامي الثلاثة), 2018; 00:05:03, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0012, Video-file My 3 dreams 17 5 2018.mp4)
      Documentary. Mohammed Mahani's love for race cars, playing oud, and karate (حُبُّ محمد مهاني لسيارات السباق وعزف العود والكاراتيه); Keywords: Gaza, childhood, family, dreams, disability (غزة، أسرة, طفولة، أحلام، إعاقة / عجز); Associated university/location: Birzeit University's program in Gaza (جامعة بيرزيت), Gaza.
  - Mahmoud Awad
    - Seekers for Life (باحثون عن حياه), 2017; 00:04:32, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0013, Video-file Seekers For Life.mp4)
      Documentary. Gaza's used clothing market (سوق غزة للملابس المستعمَلَة); Keywords: Gaza, political commentary, economic conditions (غزة، تعليق سياسي, الاقتصاد); Associated university/location: Al-Aqsa University (جامعة الأقصى), Gaza.
  - Shayma' Awadeh (شَيماء شيماء عواودة)
    - 4th Floor (طابق رقم ٤), 2018; 00:06:00, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0014, Video-file 4th Floor by Shayma Awadeh.mp4)
      Fiction. A young woman meets the neighbors on move-in day (امرأة شابة تلتقي بالجيران في يوم الانتقال); Keywords: women's roles, social commentary (تعليق اجتماعي، أدوار النساء); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Thaer Al Azzah (ثائر عبد الرحمن العزة)
    - Coffee Pot (دلة قهوة), 2018; 00:09:24, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0015, Video-file Coffee pot.mp4)
      Fiction. Coffee seller Jum'a is offered a bitter job (عَرضُ عملٍ مُضنٍ لبائع القهوة اسم جمعة); Keywords: home demolitions, political commentary, employment (عمل، هدم البيوت، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Alaa Dayeh (آلاء الداية)
    - Exit (خروج), 2017; 00:03:02, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0016, Video-file Exit by Alaa Dayeh.mp4)
      Experimental. Meditations on a Jerusalem cemetery (تأملات على مقبرة مقدسية); Keywords: political commentary, East Jerusalem, dreams (أحلام، القدس الشرقية، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Omar Elemawi
    - Private Number (رقم خاص), 2012; 00:08:03, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0017, Video-file Private Number.mp4)
      Fiction. An unexpected warning in Gaza (تحذير غير مُتَوَقَّع في غزة); Keywords: Gaza, political commentary (غزة، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Al-Aqsa University (جامعة الأقصى), Gaza.
  - Mohammed S. Ewais (محمد سمير محمد عويص)
    - We Love Life, 2015; 00:07:13, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0018, Video-file We Love Life.mp4)
      Documentary. Portrait of graffiti artist Bilal Khaled (بورتريه جرافِتي للفنان بلال خالد); Keywords: Gaza, arts, social/political commentary (غزة، فنون، تعليق اجتماعي/سياسي); Associated university/location: Al-Aqsa University/Birzeit University's program in Gaza
  - Amjad M. A. Al Fayoumi
    - Dema (ديما ), 2015; 00:03:15, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0019, Video-file Dema.mp4)
      Fiction. Gaza: too young to be a bride (غزة: صغيرة السن بَعْد كي تصبح عروساً); Keywords: Gaza, children, social commentary (غزة, طفولة، تعليق اجتماعي); Associated university/location: Al-Azhar University (جامعة الأزهر بغزة‎), Gaza.
  - Sanabel Al-Hoot, Salam Yahya, and Renad Nasser (سنابل الحوت…)
    - Reporter, Suspended (مراسل مع وقف التنفيذ), 2015; 00:04:35, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0020, Video-file Reporter suspended.mp4)
      Fiction. One child's comedic view of the media coverage in Palestine (مشهد كوميدي منفرد لطفل في التغطية الإعلامية في فلسطين); Keywords: childhood, social/political commentary, family life (أسرة، طفولة، تعليق اجتماعي/سياسي); Associated university/location: Al-Quds University Institute of Modern Media (جامعة القدس), Ramallah.
  - Mohammad Houshieh and Lana Sadaqa
    - A Pen from Majddo (قلم من مجدو), 2017; 00:10:06, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0021, Video-file PenFromMajddo.mp4)
      Fiction. The risky hopes for one couple divided by incarceration (الآمال المحفوفة بالمخاطر لزوجين يُباعد بينهما السجن); Keywords: incarceration, family, social/political commentary (أسرة، سَجن / احتجاز، تعليق اجتماعي/سياسي); Associated university/location: Al-Quds Ramallah (جامعة القدس), Ramallah.
  - Wisam Al-Jafari (وسام الجعفري)
    - Mask, 2017; 00:03:02, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0022, Video-file Mask.mp4)
      Experimental. A visual and aural deconstruction (التفكيك السمعي البصري); Keywords: political commentary (تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
    - Ambience (امبيانس), 2018; 00:14:53, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0023, Video-file Ambience_final.mp4)
      Fiction. The sounds of Deheishe refugee camp lead to frustration and appreciation (أصوات مخيم الدهيشة للاجئين تُفضِي إلى إحباط وتقدير في آنٍ واحد); Keywords: refugee camp life, family, social/political commentary (حياة مخيم اللاجئين، أسرة، تعليق اجتماعي/سياسي); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
    - Congratulations for the New Wall Paint (مبروك الدهان), 2016; 00:07:15, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0024, Video-file Congratulations for the new wall Paint.mp4)
      Sisyphus of the Dheisheh refugee camp. (سيزيف مخيم الدهيشة للاجئين -- في الأساطير اليونانية، يُحكَم على سيزيف بدحرجة كُرَة صخرية ضخمة إلى أعلى تلة والتي كانت تعاود التدحرج لأسفل التلة بعدما كانت تقترب من الوصول إلى القمة، وقد ظل سيزيف يعيد الكَرَّة للأبد.); Keywords: refugee camp life, social/political commentary. (حياة مخيم اللاجئين، تعليق اجتماعي/سياسي); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
    - Day 79 (اليوم 79), 2014; 00:10:20, 1280x720 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0025, Video-file Day 79.mp4)
      Fiction. Detained in a theater of the absurd (مُحتَجَز في مسرح عبثي); Keywords: incarceration, political commentary (سَجن / احتجاز، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Yaser Jodallah and Ahmad Al-Bazz ( ياسر جودالله احمد البظ)
    - To My Mother (اليك امي), 2014; 00:21:00, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0026, Video-file To My Mother Doc Final.mp4)
      Documentary. The occupation's impact on one family (الأثر المأساوي للاحتلال على العائلة الواحدة); Keywords: political commentary, family life, women's roles, incarceration (أسرة، أدوار النساء، سَجن / احتجاز، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: An-Najah University (جامعة النجاح الوطنية), Nablus.
  - Abeer Kaabnah (عبير كعابنة)
    - Luster of the Middle of the Desert (بريق وسط الصحراء), 2019; 00:13:05, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0027, Video-file Luster of the Desert by abeer kaabnah.mp4)
      Documentary. An ordinary school day in Mu'arrajat (يوم مدرسي اعتيادي في المُعَرَّجات); Keywords: childhood, education, family (أسرة, طفولة); Associated university/location: Birzeit University (جامعة بيرزيت), Birzeit.
  - Aya Ahmed Matrabie (آية المتربيعي)
    - Dara (دارة), 2019; 00:03:21, 840x474 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0028, Video-file Dara by Aya Matrabie.mov)
      Documentary. Creativity in needlepoint circles, in Gaza (الإبداع في دوائر التطريز الإبري، في غزة); Keywords: Gaza, arts, employment (غزة، عمل، فنون); Associated university/location: Theater Day Productions film course (أيام المسرح), Gaza.
  - Ali Hamdan Okeh (علي عكة)
    - Window (شبك), 2018; 00:07:00, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0029, Video-file Window by Ali H Okeh.mp4)
      Fiction. Sightseeing near Askar refugee camp (زيارة المعالم البارزة بالقرب من مخيم عسكر للاجئين); Keywords: childhood, refugee camp life (حياة مخيم اللاجئين، طفولة); Associated university/location: Al-Quds University Abu Dis (جامعة القدس), Jerusalem.
  - Yousef Salhi (يوسف الصالحي)
    - Memory of a Fish (ذاكرة السمكة), 2017; 00:06:30, 1280x720 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0030, Video-file memory of a fish ذاكرة السمكة.mp4)
      Fiction. The power of a pet fish (التأثير الكبير لسمكة حوض منزلية); Keywords: childhood, family (أسرة, طفولة); Associated university/location: Birzeit University (جامعة بيرزيت), Birzeit.
  - Mohammed Shalodi
    - Wa'ad (وعد), 2017; 00:15:37, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0031, Video-file wa'ad.mp4)
      Documentary. Art and politics at an Israeli art school (الفن والسياسة في مدرسة إسرائيلية للفنون); Keywords: education, arts, women's roles, East Jerusalem (أدوار النساء، القدس الشرقية، فنون); Associated university/location: Dar Al-Kalima University College of Arts & Culture (دار الكلمة الجامعية), Bethlehem.
  - Naser Shatat
    - In Dura Parkour (في دورا باركور), 2016; 00:09:19, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0032, Video-file In Dura Parkour.mp4)
      Documentary. The guys and the stunts (الفِتيَة والأعمال البارعة); Keywords: childhood, athletics/sports (طفولة، رياضة); Associated university/location: Hebron University (جامعة الخليل), Hebron.
  - Khaled Tuaima (خالد طعيمة)
    - The Cage (القفص), 2016; 00:06:42, 1280x720 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0033, Video-file The Cage.mp4)
      Documentary. Catching birds with Jabalia refugee camp's Mohammed Halawa (اصطياد العصافير مع محمد حلاوة من مخيم جباليا للاجئين.); Keywords: Gaza, employment, family, political commentary (غزة، أسرة، عمل، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Birzeit University's program in Gaza (جامعة بيرزيت), Gaza.
    - Parkour on the Rubble of Gaza (رياضة الباركور فوق ركام غزة), 2014; 00:02:33, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0034, Video-file Parkour on the Rubble of Gaza (1080p).mp4)
      Documentary. A team of athletic daredevils (فريق من الرياضيين البارعين); Keywords: Gaza, athletics/sports (غزة، رياضة); Associated university/location: Birzeit University's program in Gaza (جامعة بيرزيت), Gaza.
  - Tala Zeitawi
    - The In-Between, 2017; 00:10:02, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0035, Video-file The InBetween.mp4)
      Documentary. A family survives (عائلة تصمد في مخيم مؤقت صغير); Keywords: family life, childhood, social commentary, home demolition (أسرة, طفولة، هدم البيوت، تعليق اجتماعي); Associated university/location: Al-Quds Bard College
- Films shown at the 2020 Duke University Festival of Student Films From Palestine, 2019-2020; 25 items
  Genre and single-line descriptions of the films were provided by the filmmakers. Series includes still images from films and of film makers, along with a program from the 2020 Duke Festival of Student Films from Palestine.
  - Mai Alami (مي العلمي)
    - Amigo (اميجو), 2020; 00:02:57, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0036, Video-file Amigo.mp4)
      Documentary. In Gaza during the pandemic, a girl and her horse. (في غزة خلال الجائحة ، فتاة وحصانها.); Keywords: Gaza, childhood (غزة، طفولة، رياضة ); Associated university/location: Filmlab Palestine (فيلم لاب: فلسطين), Gaza
  - Maysa Al-Shaer (ميساء الشاعر)
    - When is the Wedding (ايمتا العرس؟), 2020; 00:03:13, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0037, Video-file When is the Wedding.mp4)
      Documentary. Coronavirus versus Wedding (فيروس كورونا والعرس); Keywords: women's roles, health (أدوار النساء، صحة); Associated university/location: Shashat Women Cinema (شاشات سينما المرأة), Jenin
  - Fatma Adel Qasem Alqadi (فاطمة عادل قاسم القاضي)
    - Yara (يارا), 2020; 00:02:25, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0038, Video-file Yara.mp4)
      Documentary. A candid message from Gaza (رسالة من غزة); Keywords: Gaza, childhood (غزة,طفولة ); Associated university/location: Al-Aqsa University (جامعة الأقصى), Gaza
  - Anas Ashreef (أنس جمال محمودالشريف)
    - Dream of Return (حلم العود), 2020; 00:04:14, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0039, Video-file Dream of Return.mp4)
      Documentary. Gaza's Great March of Return (في غزة، مسيرة العودة الكبرى); Keywords: Gaza, political commentary (غزة, طفولة، تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Al-Aqsa University (جامعة الأقصى), Gaza
  - Lara Khammash ()
    - The Hopscotch, 2020; 00:05:06, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0040, Video-file The Hopscotch.mp4)
      Fiction. A game and memory at the Wall. (الألعاب والذكريات، الجدار الفاصل); Keywords: political commentary (تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: Eastern Mediterranean University, North Cyprus (جامعة شرق البحر المتوسط), Ramallah
  - Shatha Khatib (شذى خطيب)
    - The Chair (الكرسي), 2020; 00:08:04, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0041, Video-file The Chair.mp4)
      Documentary. The world according to Sabrina Jabber. (حياة صابرينا جابر); Keywords: education, disability (تعليم، إعاقة / عجز); Associated university/location: An-Najah University (جامعة النجاح الوطنية), Nablus
  - Aya Ahmed Matrabie (آية المتربيعي)
    - The "R" (راء), 2020; 00:05:04, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0042, Video-file The R.mp4)
      Documentary. In Gaza, nurse Rewaa Najjar now runs a flower nursery. (في غزة الممرضة رواء النجار); Keywords: Gaza, women's roles, employment (غزة، أدوار النساء، عمل ); Associated university/location: Theater Day Productions (أيام المسرح), Gaza
  - Randa Owdeh (رندة عودة)
    - State of Hani Amer (دولة هاني عامر), 2020; 00:07:32, 1920x1080 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0043, Video-file State of Hani Amer.mp4)
      Documentary. Hani Amer's home is enclosed by the Wall. (منزل هاني عامر محاط ); Keywords: political commentary (تعليق سياسي); Associated university/location: An-Najah University (جامعة النجاح الوطنية), Nablus
  - Filmmaker photos and stills from films, and program from A Festival of Student Films from Palestine, 2020 (Digital-materials RL11839-SET-0044)